nipr.com 2010-11-21

# National Insurance Producer Registry

Welcome to the National Insurance Producer Registry ("NIPR") Web Site. Because your privacy on-line is very important to us, we want you to understand the NIPR's practices with regard to collecting and using your information. This privacy statement explains the privacy practices for the following NIPR Web Site, www.nipr.com. NIPR's Privacy Statement is not intended to supercede or modify the terms of any license agreement between NIPR and a third party and where inconsistent, the terms of the license agreement control. 

**Collection, Use and Disclosure of Information**  
You do not need to reveal any personally identifiable information to browse the NIPR Web Site. 

**Customer Information**  
If you order an NIPR product or register for a meeting online, NIPR may collect your name, address, telephone number, e-mail address, company name, and company size. NIPR collects this information for purposes of fulfilling orders for products, registering for meetings, and billing. NIPR may also use this information to create general mailing lists to send customers marketing and other promotional material.

NIPR collects and stores the name of the domain and host from which you access the Internet, the Internet protocol (the IP address) of the computer you are using, and the date and time you accessed the NIPR site. NIPR also tracks the pages visited within its site. This information is collected for systems administration and for analyzing and improving the value of the material available on the NIPR Web Site. 

NIPR Web Site does not use cookies at this time. Cookies are small web-generated files that are stored on your computer hard drive in order to collect information about your activities on a particular web site. However, the NIPR Web Applications including the Producer Information Network, Producer Database and Non-Resident Licensing utilize cookies to store application data while the application is in use. 

NIPR uses information collected over the Internet to process your requests, communicate back to you and improve our web sites. NIPR may share the information mentioned above with the National Association of Insurance Commissioners ("NAIC") for these purposes. NIPR does not provide customer information collected over the Internet to third parties other than in aggregated form. 

**Information Submitted in an Online Application**  
NIPR online applications, such as the Producer Information Network and Non-Resident Licensing, collect information for purposes of transmitting the information between the user and state insurance departments and/or processing the information for the user. These online applications require the user to enter into a license agreement with the NIPR. The license agreement governs the collection, use and disclosure of information while in these applications and where the terms of this Privacy Statement are inconsistent, the license agreement supercedes. 

**Security of Information**  
NIPR views security of confidential and private information as a top priority. NIPR provides secure transmission of sensitive and personal information from your computers to the NIPR's Web Server. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be absolutely secure and NIPR does not ensure or warrant the security of the transmission of information. Once the information is received by NIPR via the web site, it is stored behind a firewall. NIPR also maintains access control procedures. All NAIC and NIPR employees are aware of the privacy and security policies. Your information is only accessible to those employees who have a legitimate need for the information in order to perform their jobs. 

**Correction and Opt-Out Procedures**  
If your personally identifiable customer information changes, we will endeavor to correct, update or remove the personal data provided to us. Please visit the Web page www.nipr.com/contacts_help.htm to find the contact information or send your request for change to the Webmaster at [webpost@naic.org](mailto:webpost@naic.org). If you no longer wish to receive newsletters, promotional materials or other electronic communications, you may opt-out by replying to the e-mail and inserting the term "unsubscribe" in the subject line or by sending an e-mail to the Webmaster at [webpost@naic.org](mailto:webpost@naic.org). 

**Links to Other Web Sites**  
NIPR provides links to third-party web sites as a convenience to its users. The inclusion of any link does not imply an endorsement or recommendation of the third-party organization, its web site, or its products and services. NIPR has not reviewed and is not responsible for the privacy practices or content of such web sites. 

**Notification of Change**  
NIPR reserves the right to change its privacy policy. The most current privacy policy will be posted on the NIPR Web Site so you are always aware of what information NIPR collects, how it is used, and under what circumstances, if any, it is disclosed. If at any point NIPR decides to use personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time it was collected, NIPR will notify users by way of an e-mail. NIPR will provide a method for a user to opt-out of using their information in this different manner.
